Throughout history, people have been attracted to puzzles, from Ancient Greek riddles to brain-teasing video games, people have tried to solve problems for fun.
纵观历史，人们一直为谜题所吸引，从古希腊的谜语到考验脑力的电子游戏，人们都乐于为了乐趣去破解难题。
But what is it about these conundrums that makes us enjoy them?
可究竟是什么让我们如此喜爱这些谜题呢？
It could be that the desire to find a solution is wired into us.
或许寻求解答的渴望本就根植于我们的天性之中。
A study has shown that when people complete anagrams, it can stimulate the reward centre in the brain.
一项研究表明，人们解开变位词时，会刺激大脑中的奖赏中枢。
One of the researchers behind the study, Yongtaek Oh, suggests that problem-solving ability provides an evolutionary advantage – it can help us survive!
该研究的研究员之一吴永泽认为，解决问题的能力能带来进化上的优势——这有助于我们生存！
It's clear that this 'aha' moment is very enjoyable, but it's not just completing a puzzle that people enjoy.
显然，这种“恍然大悟”的时刻十分愉悦，但人们享受的并非只有解开谜题本身。
David Shariatmadari highlights that solving the best puzzles requires a combination of luck and skill.
大卫·沙里亚马达里强调，破解优质谜题需要运气与技巧相结合。
He points out that the element of chance makes it more open to a wide range of people, while the need for skill gives players a feeling that they are in control.
他指出，偶然性因素让谜题能面向更多人群，而对技巧的要求则让玩家拥有掌控感。
This also helps to provide a balance between being something challenging and something achievable.
这也让谜题在挑战性与可完成性之间达到了平衡。
Michael Vilensky, a psychologist at Ohio State University, tells us that puzzles offer us a situation that we can control and resolve, which can be satisfying when compared with other life challenges.
俄亥俄州立大学的心理学家迈克尔·维伦斯基表示，谜题能为我们提供一个可掌控、可解决的情境，相较于生活中的其他挑战，这种体验能带来满足感。
Other experts, such as therapist Elizabeth Hinkel, argue that by requiring concentration, puzzles can provide mindful moments away from the stresses of everyday life.
其他专家，如治疗师伊丽莎白·欣克尔则认为，谜题需要专注，能让我们获得正念时刻，远离日常生活的压力。
Puzzles can also have a social aspect, whether that's making it easy to share your scorecard on social media, or the fact that people are keen to help each other find clues and come up with the answer.
谜题还具备社交属性，无论是便于在社交媒体上分享成绩卡，还是人们热衷于互相帮忙寻找线索、得出答案。
Puzzles and fun may even be dependent on each other, researchers at Drexel University have suggested.
德雷塞尔大学的研究人员提出，谜题与乐趣甚至可能相互依存。
When looking at brain images, they found that some people preparing to do a puzzle showed activity associated with positive moods and that these people were better able to come up with solutions.
通过观察脑部影像，他们发现部分准备玩谜题的人，大脑出现了与积极情绪相关的活动，而这些人也更擅长想出解答。
They also found that subjects performed better on puzzles if they had seen a funny video beforehand.
他们还发现，实验对象如果事先观看过搞笑视频，在破解谜题时表现会更好。